Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 14 Research Topics and Materials
  - Pakistan (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Papua-New Guinea (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Paraguay (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Peru (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Philippine Republic (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Philippine Republic (cont.) (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Poland (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Portugal (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Portuguese Africa (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Punjabi (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Romansh (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Rumania (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Rwanda (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Scotland (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Senegal (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Sindhi (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Singapore (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Slovenia (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Somalia (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Republic of South Africa (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - South West Africa (Namibia) (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Soviet Union (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Africa (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Sri Lanka (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Sudan (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Swaziland (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Sweden (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Switzerland (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Taiwan (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Tanzania (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Telugu (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Thailand (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Togo (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Tongo (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Tunisia (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Tungus (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Turkey (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Turkey (cont.) (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Uganda (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Upper Volta (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Uruguay (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - USA (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - USA (cont.) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - USSR (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - USSR (cont.) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Uzbekistan (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Venezuela (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Walloon (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - West Indies (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Zambia (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include social behavior, Lapland, ethnic politics, third generation movements), 1963-75 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include France, Arabs, Arab-Israeli conflict), 1970-76 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include definitions of ethnicity, immigration and ethnicity, social concepts), 1927-76 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include attitudes, national structure, Chicago immigrants), 1965-82 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include nationalism, pluralism), 1969-74 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include Ilongots, personality, Native American language use, France), 1975-76 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include ethnic groups and the state, ethnic identification, Tunisian immigrants in Israel, Catholic Church, France), 1952-84 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include Kenya, Indonesia, Africa, Armenia, small-scale societies), 1959-75 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include French Canada, nationalism and the third world, Irish nation), 1965-71 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include social anthropology, Greek nationalism, sacred community, African nationalism, Tunisian immigrants in Israel1938-76 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Ethnicity offprints (topics include medieval Europe, Asian nationalism, group identity, Turkish moderniation), 1954-83 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements, 1990s (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements, 1980s (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements, 1980s (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements1980s (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements1980s (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Ultra-Orthodox letters and annoucements1970s (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Ultra-Orthodox magazines (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Series 15 Language Cartoons Collection
  This series contains cartoons, mostly photocopies of printed items, in English, Hebrew, and Yiddish, with a few in other languages. Some of the cartoons in Hebrew and Yiddish are on photographic slides.
  - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hebrew (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hebrew (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yiddish (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 16 J. A. Fishman Research Materials in Preparation for the Writing of His Books, 1885-1991
  This series contains research materials, revisions, correspondence, publication materials, and other items for 5 books written or contributed to by Dr. Fishman. Subseries A Reversing Language Shift includes correspondence, proofs, and revisions of the book (with handwritten edits) in addition to research materials. Subseries B Ideology, Society & Language: The Odyssey of Nathan Birnbaum includes correspondence; articles (some with Dr. Fishman's translations and notations); publication materials; and correspondence, photos, and other material relating to Nathan Birnbaum. This subseries is multilingual Hebrew/German/Yiddish/English). Subseries C "The First Congress Phenomenon: The First Congress for Language X" includes correspondence, the introduction and conclusions to the book, and research materials. Subseries D Yiddish: Turning to Life includes the table of contents, index, and preface; research materials; proofs; and correspondence. Subseries E The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival contains correspondence, research materials, coding sheets and data forms, content analysis forms, and other materials.
  - Subseries A Reversing Language Shift
    - JAF Book: Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - JAF Book: Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - JAF Book: Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Language cases (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Reversing Language Shift (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence & materials: Afrikaans; Amerindian (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence & materials: Australian (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence & materials: Australian (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence & materials: Australian (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence & materials: Australian (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Australian immigrants & aboriginals (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Australian immigrants & aboriginals (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Australian aboriginals (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Basque (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Basque materials (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Basque materials (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Basque materials (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Basque materials (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Basque materials (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Basque materials (tapes to be removed from folder) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Catalan (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Catalan materials (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Catalan (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - French in Quebec (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - French in Canada (outside Quebec) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - French in Canada (outside Quebec) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - French in Canada & Quebec (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: French in Canada (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Frisian materials (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Frisian materials (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Frisian materials (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Frisian (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Hebrew (pre-state) materials (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hebrew materials (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Irish materials (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Irish materials (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Irish materials (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - [missing] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - [missing] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Irish (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Maori materials (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Maori (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Maori (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Maori (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Navaho (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Romansh/Ladin (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Romansh (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Romansh (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Romansh/Ladin (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Romansh/Ladin (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Sorbian (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Spanish in NYC / in the mainland (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Spanish (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Welsh (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: general and with publisher (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - First page proofs 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - First page proofs 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Second page proofs 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Second page proofs 2 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Second page proofs 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Pages to correct (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Revised version of book (with JAF handwritten revisions) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Revised version of book (with JAF handwritten revisions) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Revised version of book (with JAF handwritten revisions) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Revisions of book with JAF handwriting (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Revisions of book with JAF handwriting (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Final draft 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Final draft 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Final draft 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Final draft 4 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Final draft 5 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B Ideology, Society and Language: The Odyssey of Nathan Birnbaum
    - Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Articles with JAF translations and notations, 1885-1886 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Articles, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Articles [Hebrew language; Jewish newspapers] 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Articles [German language newspaper articles] 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Articles [Zionism; Jewish issues; German language articles] 1894-1897 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Articles [Zionism; Yiddish language] 1898-1902 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Articles [Hebrew and Yiddish] 1902-1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Articles with JAF translations and notations [Languages of the Jewish peoples] 1904-1905 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Articles, [East European Jews] 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles, [Jewish autonomy] 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Articles [German and Jewish language articles] 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Articles [Conference in Czernovitz] 1908 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Articles with JAF translations and notations, ["The Truth"] 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Articles [German language articles] 1909 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Articles [Americanism and the Jews] 1909-1910 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Articles [Recognition of the Jewish Nation; Galicia] 1910-1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Articles [Zionism; Yiddish language] 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Articles with JAF translations and notations [Eastern and Western Jewry] 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Articles [Ancestry of Yiddish] 1913 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Articles ["Sprachadel"] 1913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Articles ["The Dying Yiddish Language"] 1914-1916 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Articles [German and Jewish language articles] 1916-1918 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Articles ["Oppressed by Fellow Jews"] 1919 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Articles [German and Jewish language articles] 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Articles with JAF translations and notations, 1925-1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Articles, 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Articles, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Articles, 1946, 1956, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - N. Birnbaum letters (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Birnbaum in Holland, 1938 onwards (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Birnbaum in Holland, 1938 onwards (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Birnbaum in Holland (and obituaries) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Birnbaum in Holland (and obituaries) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - New post book N.B. items (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - New post book N.B. items (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: publication of book (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Publication materials (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - About Nathan Birnbaum (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Context: people, places, movements (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Context: people, places, movements (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Photocopies of Nathan Birnbaum photos (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Nathan Birnbaum: list of illustrations and sources (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - List of negatives and photographs (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Nathan Birnbaum photos (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Nathan Birnbaum slides (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Subseries C The First Congress Phenomenon: The First Congress for Language X
    - General correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Introduction to book (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Conclusions to book (& some general conclusions) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Afrikaans; Belorussian (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Catalan (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dutch; Hebrew; Hindi (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Indonesian; Korean; Macedonian; Mayan; Malay (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Polish; Quechua & Aymara; Tok Pisin (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Turkish; Ukrainian; Wolof (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries D Yiddish: Turning to Life
    - Table of contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Preparation of the index of the book (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Index (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Index (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Index (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Index (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Preface: sociohistorical perspective (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Yiddish & Hebrew (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish in America (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Corpus planning (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Status planning (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The future (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Appendix: statistical tables (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - GSF reading of first page proofs (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - GSF reading of first page proofs (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - GSF reading of first page proofs (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Second page proofs (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with publisher (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Subseries E The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival
    - The Rise and Fall of the Ethnic Revival: Research for book - general correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - coding instructions (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - content analysis and coding publications (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - Franco-American publications (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - Franco-American publications (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - Franco-American publications (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - Pennsylvania German address labels (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Rise and Fall: Research for book - Penn. German address labels (cont.) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Jewish address labels (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publications address labels (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - U5 statistics on publications (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous social news (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Asian-American organizations (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - German cultural organizations and Italian cultural organizations (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Context of Yiddish publications: code sheets (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Context of Yiddish publications: code sheets (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (cont.) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Context of Jewish publications: code sheets (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Spanish-American evaluation sheets (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Spanish-American evaluation sheets (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Churches (mostly Spanish-American) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Various addresses, lists, contacts (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Various Ethnic Resource publications (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Various Ethnic Resource publications (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Various Ethnic Resource publications (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Code sheets: rejects (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Code sheets: rejects (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Code sheets: rejects (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Code sheets: rejects (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Labels - Christian churches (all kinds) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Address labels by denomination and language (corrections) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Address labels by denomination and language (corrections) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish publications (abstracts) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish publications (abstracts) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish publications (abstracts) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish publications (abstracts) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish publications (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish organizations (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish cultural and religious gatherings (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish religious observances (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Content analysis scoring: ethno-religious observances (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Assorted Yiddish publications (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Content analysis scoring: old country references: Israel (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Content analysis scoring: Yiddish press (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Yiddish press (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish publications (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish press (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish topics (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Yiddish press (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish press (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Yiddish press (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish publications (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish publications (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish publications (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Jewish synagogues and temples: addresses (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Jewish synagogues and temples: addresses (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Jewish synagogues and temples: addresses (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Jewish synagogues and temples: addresses (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Churches: address labels (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Churches: address labels (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Churches: address labels (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Churches: address labels (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Churches - address labels (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Churches - addresses (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Churches - addresses (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Churches - addresses (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Churches - address labels (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Churches - address labels (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Churches: address labels (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Churches: lists (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Churches: address lists (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Churches: address lists (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Content analysis scoring: Anglo-Jewish press (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - IBM data coding forms (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - IBM data collection coding forms (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Publications coding (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - IBM data collection coding forms (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Assorted publications and coding notes (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Radio & television (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Radio & television (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Publications, periodical, brochures (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Publications, periodical, brochures (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Publications, publishers, periodicals (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Book publishers (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Book publishers & periodicals (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Publications: Issue profile summary totals: German (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Data information state by state count (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Schools - unprocessed (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: El Hispano (1976 & 1968) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: El Continental (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: Diario las Americas (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: El Diario la Prensa (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: La Opinion (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: Nuestro; El Informador (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Coding of Spanish publications: La Gaceta; Grafica; El Clarin (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Profiles of issue publications: French (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - IBM data coding forms - German publications (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - IBM data forms - German (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - IBM coding forms: Yiddish publications: Forverts (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - IBM data coding forms: Yiddish publications: Kulture un Leln; Morgn Frayhayt (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - IBM coding forms: Yiddish publications: Afn Shvel, Algemeyner Zhurnal (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - IBM data coding forms: Yiddish publications: Pionern Froyen; D. Toyrevelt (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - IBM data coding forms: Yiddish publications: D. Tsukunft; Undzer Tsayt der Verer, der Yid (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - IBM data coding forms: Yiddish publications: D. Yidishe Heym; Yidisher Kemfer; Dos Yidishe Vort (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Profiles of issue publications: Yiddish (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Profiles of issue publications: Yiddish (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Profiles of issue publications: Yiddish (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - IBM data coding forms: Anglo-Jewish publications (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - IBM data coding forms: Anglo-Jewish publications (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - IBM data coding forms: Anglo-Jewish publications (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Profiles of issue publications: Anglo-Jewish (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Linguistic analysis (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - IBM data coding forms: El Diario - La Prensa (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - IBM data coding forms: Spanish press (assorted) (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - IBM data coding forms: El Sol de Texas (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - IBM data coding forms: La Opinion (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Churches: lists and response forms (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Content analysis scoring: Spanish press (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Content analysis scoring: Spanish press (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Rise and Fall - content analysis scoring: Spanish press (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Rise and Fall - content analysis scoring: Spanish press (Box 20, Folder 4)